Let's talk now about how to change the hook on a lure.
Most of your lures, especially ice fishing jigs, have a metal ring at the end of them and that's how the hook goes on.
Lures always come with a hook, but sometimes it's not the hook you want.
For example, some, most come with a treble hook, but in some states using a treble hook with bait while ice fishing is illegal, so with those you'd always want to change them out.
In other states there aren't regulations like that, but you might still want to change them for other reasons.
So I've got a single hook on this lure right now.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to change it to a treble hook.
I'm just going to put my nail, my thumbnail into that ring, bend it apart and now I'm going to start the hook that I want to take off backwards.
So that's going there.
While I do that I'm going to insert the treble hook at the same time and then simply just wind everything back to me.
The treble hook, as you can see, is going to be pushing the single hook that I want to take off, and I'm just going to continue that until the single hook comes off and now I've got my treble on my lure.